<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on DrGos</title><link>https://drgos.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on DrGos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drgos.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Factory Pattern</title><link>https://drgos.com/p/factory-pattern/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drgos.com/p/factory-pattern/</guid><description>Factory pattern or Factory Method Pattern is one of the most basic and most used design patterns in OOP languages. This is a creational type pattern and this pattern provides one of the best ways to create different objects without exposing the creation logic and exposing it using a common interface.
To make it easier to understand, think of a car factory. The car factory produces multiple car types, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly how the cars are produced, how much of the underlying technology and components they share, but you don&amp;rsquo;t care about that.</description></item><item><title>Design Patterns Intro</title><link>https://drgos.com/p/design-patterns-intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drgos.com/p/design-patterns-intro/</guid><description>There is an old saying, &amp;ldquo;If the only tool you have is a hammer, you will start treating all your problems like a nail.”
This quote dates back to 1964 and Abraham Kaplan, whose first wording was actually:
&amp;ldquo;Give a small boy a hammer and he will find that everything he encounters needs a pounding.&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that in Software Engineering interviews there is a big accent on algorithms and data structures, but not on design patterns, at least not when you are starting out.</description></item><item><title>How to host your site on Github for free!</title><link>https://drgos.com/p/how-to-host-your-site-on-github-for-free/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://drgos.com/p/how-to-host-your-site-on-github-for-free/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start a blog and what better hello world post than how I&amp;rsquo;ve set it up. But first lets talk about what is Hugo.
What is Hugo? 2560px-Logo_of_Hugo_the_static_website_generator.svg.png
According to their site Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator written in Go, and designed to make website creation fun again.
Put it in layman terms Hugo is a tool that generates a full static HTML website based on raw data and a set of templates.</description></item></channel></rss>